我有话要说
I have something to say.
- 如果又是要说马桶坐垫没放下来... - 不 并不是
- If it's about the lavatory seat again... - No, it's not.
和马桶圈没什么关系
It's very much not.
- 斯文向我求婚了 - 你拒绝了
- Sven has proposed. - Say no.
我答应了
And I have said yes.
我爱你的父亲 但是我空窗了
I adored your father, but I haven't had a gentleman in my life
整整八年时间
for eight years.
斯文足智多谋 英俊 而且我爱他
And Sven is resourceful and he's handsome and I love him.
- 这消息真令人激动 - 谢谢你 亲爱的
- This is so exciting. - Thank you, darling.
- 各位早上好 - 早上好 南希
- Morning, everyone. - Morning, Nancy.
- 南希 - 南希
- Nance. - Nancy.
- 好想你 - 我也想你
- Missed you. - Oh, missed you, too.
无论如何 现在可以聊一下我了吗
Anyway, can we talk about me
因为我刚告诉你们我快要结婚了
because I have just told you I'm getting married.
我们肯定会审问他的
We will need to interview him.
要结婚的人是你还是我
Who is getting married, you or me?
你以后也会审问我们未来的对象
I'm sure you'll want to run your eyes over our potential spouses.
好吧
Fine.
德雷尔一家 第一季 第六集
为什么你要养这么多动物
Why you have them, all of these animals?
跟你拥有自己的家庭是一个道理
The same reason you have a family.
我母亲的功劳
My mother make me.
我通常是为了享受它们的陪伴
Well, normally, it's to enjoy their company.
但你说得对 鲁格勒斯雅 我应该邀请人们
But you're right, Lugaretzia, I should invite people
来感受动物的陪伴
to come and enjoy them, too.
为此 我需要更多的动物
I might need some more.
工作太无聊
Work is so boring.
我被困在室内 现在她才把百叶窗拉开
I'm stuck indoors, and she's drawn the shutters now.
这感觉就像在矿井下工作
It's like I'm working down a mine.
但这个矿井里都是路易十五世风格的家具
A mine filled with Louis Quinze furniture.
如果她没有郁郁寡欢的话
If she didn't have this annoying depression thing,
我们早就可以去旅游 逛街 我还可以跟小天使聊天
we'd go travelling and shopping, and I'd chat to Angel.
配崔迪斯医生帮不上忙吗
Can't Dr Petridis help?
噢 我自己可以搞定
Oh, I'll get through it.
不 我说的是伯爵夫人
No, help the Countess?
不 她会把这归咎给她丈夫的死亡
No. She blames it on the shock of her husband dying.
从那以后她的世界便越来越小
Her world's been smaller ever since.
照这样下去 她会死在衣橱里
At this rate, she'll end up in a wardrobe.
说真的 钱买不到你要的快乐 不是吗
You know, truly, money can't buy you happiness, can it?
但可以买一些迷人的高级时装 把不开心裹起来
But it can buy you some lovely haute couture to be unhappy in.
幸亏我们没有钱
It's just as well, we don't have any money,
确实 斯文也没有
really, and neither does Sven.
那你还想结婚吗
Are you still wanting to get married?
今早过后吗
Since this morning?
是的 我想是的
Erm... yes, I think so.
很好 走着瞧吧
Well, we'll see.
我们希望你能把答案写在纸上
We'd like your answers down on paper, please.
抱歉 我的律师建议我不要写任何东西
Sorry, my lawyers advised me not to put anything in writing.
其实 我不关心
Can I just say, I don't
我母亲嫁给谁 我只喜欢审问这个环节
care who my mother marries, I'm enjoying this.
来 为什么你想娶德雷尔夫人
Come on, why do you want to marry Mrs Durrell?
- 因为我爱她 - 很好 说起来倒轻松
- Because I love her. - Well, that's easy to say.
- 是的 的确 - 该死的 他很不错
- Yes, it is. - Damn, he's good.
当然 钱不是万能
Money isn't everything, of course,
但身无分文 这是真的吗
but is it true you don't have any?
我有一些地 身体好 而且乐观向上
I have some land, I am rich in strength and in spirit.
- 你可以送一只山羊给我吗 - 不
- May I have one of your goats? - No.
伏尔泰说过上帝创造了性 神父创造了婚姻
Voltaire said that God created sex and priests created marriage.
- 你有任何想法吗 - 没有
- Thoughts? - None.
我回家晚了 还带着一个帅哥
I come home late with a handsome boy,
想跟他互相了解
wanting to get to know each other better.
进一步了解 你会怎么做
Much better. What do you do?
快点回答
I'll have to hurry you.
我先问问你母亲
I ask your mother.
你好 斯文 你正在接受德雷尔全家的攻击吗
Hello, Sven. So you're getting the full Durrells assault?
没错
Yes.
抱歉 请你先离开 你不是德雷尔家的人
Sorry, but would you leave, please? You're not one of us.
你有想过跟我们的母亲生孩子吗
Are you thinking of having children with our mother?
这主意可不太好
Because that would be a bad idea.
玩笑可以适可而止了吗
I think the joke is over now, don't you?
- 我可以借一只山羊吗 - 我会跟它们商量一下
- May I borrow a goat? - I will discuss it with them.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得自己不属于这里
I feel like an intruder in this house.
- 为什么 - 你的家人分开时都很友好
- Why? - Your family are fine individually.
- 也不是这样 - 但在一起的时候
- Well, not really. - But together,
感觉就像有一群蜜蜂一样 围着我嗡嗡叫
it's like living with bees, buzzing in my face,
总是刺我
little stings the whole time.
这里真的太拥挤了
And it's really crowded.
你可以跟我一样 吼他们
Just do what I do, shout at them.
- 我不可以 他们不是我的家人 - 你可以的
- I can't, they're not my family. - You really can.
我们可以一起吼他们
We'll do it together.
我们去找一个自己的小天地吧
Let's find a place of our own.
我们二十二岁了 拉里
We're 22, Larry.
当然
Of course.
我很愿意
Sure. I'd love that.
你在担心你母亲会说什么 是吗
You're worried about what your mother will say, aren't you?
- 是的 我在担心 - 嗯
- Yes, I am. - Hm.
其他两个裁判在哪
Where are the other two judges?
拉里和南希在亲热
Larry and Nancy are canoodling.
格里在开德雷尔动物园
And Gerry's opening the Durrell Zoo.
噢 那我可以嫁给斯文了吗
Oh. So, may I marry Sven?
我们都喜欢他
Well, we like him.
他很迷人 不是吗
He's lovely, isn't he?
我们担心他太年轻太帅气了
Well, we... we're worried he's a bit too young and handsome.
- 我们有吗 - 有吗
- Are we? - Are we?
听着 如果你嫁给一个老头
Look, if you marry an old chap
就算婚姻失败 他也活不了那么久
and it goes wrong, he won't be alive that long.
请牢记于心
Do bear that in mind.
动物园 免费观看各种动物
你不必这样 德雷尔夫人
You don't have to do this, Mrs Durrells.
- 我知道 - 告诉他 你答应他求婚时思绪不安
- I know. - Tell him your mind was disturbed when you said yes.
- 你为什么不喜欢斯文 - 没什么
- What have you got against Sven? - Nothing.
除了他既不是希腊人也不是英国人之外
Except he's not Greek and he's not British.
很多人也不是啊 斯皮罗斯
Well, a lot of people aren't, Spiros.
若你坚持要再婚 选我的朋友拉布罗斯吧
If you must marry again, have my friend Labros.
你会有吃不完的面包
You will never run out of bread.
- 他是烘焙师吗 - 不 他只是喜欢面包而已
- Is he a baker? - No, he just likes bread.
我们可以出发了吗
Shall we go?
- 我们现在去哪里 - 斯文家
- Where are we going? - Sven's house.
不
No!
你通过面试了 干得好
Well done for passing your audition.
他们都是好伙伴
They are good company.
我借了一只羊给格里 还在跟莱斯利做思想工作
I'm lending Gerry a goat and I am working on Leslie.
那你想什么时候结婚
So, when do you want to get married?
不急
There's no rush.
我们快点结婚吧
Let's do it soon.
你指的具体有多快
What do you mean by soon?
一周 或者两周
A week, two.
很好
Well...
我们不该再进一步了解对方吗
shouldn't we get to know each other better first?
不 结婚是件浪漫 有趣的事情
No. It's romantic, fun.
斯文 你把浅显易懂的秘密说出来了
You're revealing hidden shallows, Sven.
我喜欢
I like it.
而且 在结婚之前
Also, I don't believe in...
我不想做那种事
you know, before marriage.
看来我们要尽快结婚了
Oh. Well, we'd better get married quickly, then.
我一直以来都为我的家庭而活
I've been living for my family for so long.
是时候开始为自己而活了
It's time I started living for myself.
还有为你而活
And for you.
所以 两周后举行婚礼
So, in two weeks... a wedding.
我希望阿莱科脾气好点
I do hope Alecko isn't grumpy.
是的 我们必须阻止游客触摸动物
Yes, we must discourage touching the exhibits.
在雅典动物园里 我看见一只貘咬断了游客的手指
In Athens Zoo, I saw a tapir bite off a visitor's finger.
- 太可怕了 - 同时也很奢侈 它们毕竟是草食动物
- How horrible. - And wasteful, as they are herbivores.
马戈 你在动物王国里找到乐趣了吗
Margo, are you discovering an interest in the animal kingdom?
不 西奥 你无所不知
No. Theo, you know everything,
为什么伯爵夫人不离开她的别墅
why won't my Countess leave her villa?
这是因为她有公共场所恐惧症
This is, of course, agoraphobia,
源于希腊语 "agorafovia"
from the Greek... agorafovia, hooray!
害怕集市这些地方
Fear of the marketplaces.
太奇葩了 我爱购物
That's so odd. I love shopping.
这是对空地产生的恐惧 而并不只是市场
The fear is of the open space, rather than the market.
那我该如何治愈她
Oh. So how can I cure her?
这种症状出于自我失控
It can stem from feeling out of control,
所以他人的安慰和放松能够帮助她
so reassurance and relaxation may help.
太好了 谢谢你
Good. Thank you.
- 但是大脑是一个复杂的器官 - 她已经走了
- But the brain is a complex organ, which... - She's gone.
我并不觉得德雷尔家的大脑有那么复杂
I don't think Durrell brains are that complex.
斯文和我决定两周后结婚
Sven and I have decided to get married in two weeks.
为什么 你怀孕了吗
Why? Are you pregnant?
当然没有
No!
我们只想尽快把事情办掉 因为这既浪漫又有趣
We just want to do it soon because, well, it's romantic and fun.
不 你不能这样做 我们还有疑虑
No, you can't, we still have our doubts.
两周的时间太短 找不到礼服
That's not long enough to find a dress.
我已经结过一次婚了
Oh, I've been married once,
马戈 会找到合适的衣服
Margo, I'll just find something suitable
再插上一支康乃馨
and stick a carnation on it.
你是指你找不到礼服吧
You were talking about your dress, weren't you?
不 不完全是
No. Not entirely.
- 祝贺你 德雷尔夫人 - 谢谢你 南希
- Congratulations, Mrs Durrell. - Well, thank you, Nancy.
为什么要等 打铁趁热呗
Why wait? Strike while the iron's hot.
没有比此刻更好了
There's no time like the present.
这在说什么 又要吵架吗
What is this, platitudes day?
所以 你跟南希为什么吵架
So, why are you and Nancy rowing?
- 我很高兴你提起了这件事 - 亲爱的
- I'm glad you brought that up. - Oh, dear.
南希觉得 我认同她的看法 但其实不是
Nancy feels, and, well, I agree with her, but less so...
- 天啊 拉里  - 我们...
- Oh, bloody hell, Larry. - OK, we...
我的意思是南希... 还有我内心的一部分...
by which I mean Nancy, but a proportion of me...
想找一个属于二人的小天地
want to find our own place to live.
不 你不是这么想的
No, you don't.
- 嗯 - 我们五口人在这里过得很好啊
- Well... - We have fun here, don't we, the five of us?
六口人
Six.
我们六个 不吵架时 不是相处得很愉快吗
The six of us, we... we have fun, when we're not arguing.
- 是南希的主意吗 - 无论如何 你嫁给斯文
- Was this Nancy's idea? - Everything's changing, anyway,
- 一切都在变化 - 但最重要的是
- with you marrying Sven. - But the important things, th-th-the
我们一家人在一起 这是不会改变的
being together, that's not changing.
而且搬到外面你也负担不起 拉里 你并没有钱
And you can't afford to move out, Larry, you're broke.
你也是
So are you.
我 我可以写作
I... I can write for money.
我也很伤心
I'm sad, too.
只是以防万一
Erm... just in case this helps at all,
如果拉里离开我们也会支持他
we think it's fine if Larry leaves.
- 是的 - 没错
- We do. - Yeah.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
早上好 南希
Morning, Nancy.
- 你好 德雷尔夫人 - 我泡了一些茶给你
- Hello, Mrs Durrell. - I brought you some tea.
- 不错的玫瑰花茶 - 谢谢你
- Nice cup of rosie. - Thank you.
所以 我听说你和拉里在考虑
So, er... I hear you and Larry are thinking about
- 找一个属于你们的地方 - 是的
- finding a place of your own? - Yes.
- 不是因为... - 听着 我完全理解
- Now, it's not because... - Look, I completely understand.
我担心的不仅是这个
My concerns are broader.
是吗
Oh?
我觉得 南希你是一个年轻阳光的女孩
I suppose I'm thinking, does Nancy, a bright young thing,
真的想葬身于 我们坦白说吧
really want to bury herself away on a... let's face it,
一个简陋的地中海岛屿吗
a primitive Mediterranean island?
是的
Well, you have.
拉里喜欢这里
Larry likes it here.
是的 他在科孚文思泉涌
Yes, and he writes really well on Corfu.
所以 那为什么你还建议我带他走
So why are you suggesting I take him away?
不 我只是在说你
No, I was just talking about you.
噢
Oh.
你还很年轻 不用这么快安顿下来
See, you're very young to settle down.
我接下来的话可能不太中听
And this is going to sound horrid,
但是我觉得拉里不是那么专一
but I don't believe Larry's got other women out of his system.
动物管理员先生
Mr Zookeeper!
- 给你一头羊 - 谢谢你 斯文
- Have a goat. - Thanks, Sven.
还有...
And...
我在路上找到的一只乌龟
A tortoise I found on the way.
一开始人来得不多吧
Slow start, huh?
是啊 但是我四处宣传了一下
Yes, but I cycled round telling people
他们肯定在来的路上了
so I'm sure they're on their way.
- 你妈妈在这儿吗 - 不在 她进城了
- Is your mummy here? - No, she's gone into town.
你不回来为我工作了 是吗
You're not coming back to work for me, are you?
不了 谢谢 我把脚趾撞到你那愚蠢的铲子上了
No, thanks. I banged my toe on your cretinous shovel.
还有啊 我喝了你一点茴香酒
Look, by the way, I had some of your ouzo.
- 那是药用的 - 我发现了
- It was medicinal. - I noticed.
祝贺你这么短时间就能结成婚
And congratulations on the emergency wedding thing.
急什么呀
What's the hurry?
干嘛要拖着
Why wait?
你要知道 不结婚也能啪啪啪
You can make whoopee outside marriage, you know.
如果我要和一位女性行房 我希望她有名分
If I'm going to make love to a woman, I want it to be official.
你之前没和女人做过吗
You've never made love to a woman?
当然做过 不然我平时干什么
Of course I have. What else would I be doing?
是啊 你问到我了
No, you've got me there.
不会吧
No.
同性恋是什么意思
What is homosexuality?
你是怎么长这么大的
Where have you been all your life?
homo与home谐音
- 主要是在外面打猎 - 是在家做爱的意思吗
- Outside, mainly, shooting. - Is it sex in a home?
- 不是 - 那我不猜了
- No. - I give up, then.
- 我也许知道 - 你当然知道了
- I think I might know. - Of course you do.
难道不是两个男性交配吗
Isn't it when two males try to mate?
啊 我知道了
Oh, yes, I do know what that is.
那是非法的 应当如此
It's illegal, and rightly so,
我们都不应该谈论这件事
we shouldn't even be talking about it.
- 这种情况出现多久了 - 一直都有
- How long has it been going on? - For ever.
古希腊人特别热衷这个
The ancient Greeks couldn't get enough of it.
等一等 斯文要嫁给母亲 他怎么可能是同性恋
Wait, how can Sven be homosexual if he's marrying Mother?
因为他一直在掩藏这件事
Because he's been hiding it.
但也可能是我错了
But I may be mistaken.
我应该告诉母亲吗
Should I tell Mother?
你怎么了 拉里 你一般不是很自信吗
What's up with you, Larry? You're normally so sure of yourself.
是啊 最近生活有些艰辛
Well, life's a bit fraught at the moment.
南希不跟我说话了
Nancy isn't talking to me.
这是件好事 不是吗
Well, that's a good thing, isn't it?
马克斯给你寄来一封明信片
Oh, there's a postcard for you from Max.
最亲爱的马戈
我希望你能顺利收到这封信
我期待在不久之后看到你美丽的脸庞
我特别想你
这边的生活平淡得无聊
期待我们再会
全部的爱
马克斯
谢谢你 德米特里斯
Oh, thank you, Demetrios.
我是丹尼斯
Dennis.
瞧瞧这些 美得惊人
Look at those. Heart stopping.
我的母亲一周后就要结婚了
My mother's getting married in a week.
这么快 她怀孕了吗
So quick. Is she pregnant?
没有
No.
- 我们很希望您能来 - 你知道我从来不离开别墅的
- We'd love it if you'd come. - You know I never leave the villa.
真是可惜 因为我很想参加婚礼的
A pity, really, cos I do love a wedding.
这婚礼也好不到哪儿去
And it will be hopeless
因为我们对时尚一窍不通
because none of us have a clue about style.
- 我也许能帮上忙 - 真的可以吗
- I may be able to help. - Would you?
婚宴要在家里举办 来我们家出点主意吧
The reception's at home. Come to our house and get some ideas.
大家都加把劲啊 把这场婚礼办好
Come on, everyone, let's organise this wedding!
我觉得我们应该供应一些小香肠
I think we should serve those little sausages.
大家都喜欢吃这个的吧
Everybody loves those, don't they?
这就是你的计划吗
That's your big plan, is it?
斯文是希腊正统教的
Well, Sven is Greek Orthodox
尽管他也喜欢告白那一部分
though he likes the confession part,
还有帽子 所以都计划好了
he says, and the hats. So it's all planned.
如果这次婚礼不能如愿进行...
Look if this wedding does go ahead, I...
亲爱的 这次婚礼会进行的
Darling, this wedding is going ahead,
如果你可以帮我安排一下
and I would really like it
我会非常高兴的
if you could arrange it for me, please.
让我们组一个仪仗队
OK, well, let's form a guard of honour
每一年都为你开一枪
and fire a shot for every year of your life.
拉里 你有什么主意吗
Er... Larry, any ideas?
- 比这更好的主意 - 没有
- Better ones? - No.
鲁格勒斯雅 明天厨房就交给你了
Lugaretzia, the kitchen is all yours tomorrow,
斯文和我要在他家吃一顿庆祝晚宴
Sven and I are having a celebratory supper at his house.
- 我做一个结婚蛋糕 - 带着白色糖衣的吗
- I make wedding cake. - Oh, with white icing?
不 棕色的 用梅干做
No. Brown, with prunes.
这是祖传的配方
Family recipe.
格里
Gerry!
我带来一些热情的访客 来参观你的动物园
I bring you enthusiastic visitors to your zoo.
这边请
Please come this way.
有问题尽管问
Do ask questions.
斯皮罗斯 明天下午三点
Spiros, please can I book your car
- 你可以把车开到别墅那里吗 - 当然可以
- for three o'clock tomorrow at the villa? - Of course.
- 要去购物吗 - 不是 我要把某人的心病治好
- Shopping? - No. I'm curing someone.
这些螳螂只有一只耳朵 长在它们的腹部
These mantis have only one ear, here on their abdomen.
常见的乌龟... 虽然常见 但是一点也不无聊
The common tortoise... common, but anything but boring.
慢点开 聊一些轻松的小话题
Drive slowly, and keep the conversation relaxing and frothy.
我的朋友 管家先生
My friend, the butler.
当管家感觉怎么样啊
How's the butling?
只能说时好时坏吧
I have my good days and my bad days.
这种感觉真不错吧
Well, this is all very nice.
快停车
Stop the car!
哎呀 伯爵夫人 这太荒谬了
Come on, Countess, this is ridiculous.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
准备得怎么样了
How are the preparations going?
我做了这个特别时髦的剪贴板
Well, I've made this very snazzy clipboard.
对南希友好点 别把炉子点着了
Oh. Be nice to Nancy and don't set the oven on fire.
- 走吧 母亲 我们没事的 - 只是我很久没有
- Leave, mother, we'll be fine. - It's just been such a long time
- 让你们晚上单独在家了 - 一点没错啊
- since I've left you on your own for the evening. - Exactly.
早就该这样了
It's high time.
- 在斯文家玩得开心 - 我不会回来得太晚
- Have fun at Sven's. - I won't be late.
难道你不是早上再回来吗
Shouldn't you be back in the morning?
- 不啊 为什么 - 看看是不是和之前一样
- No, why? - See if you get on, as it were.
有没有火花
Check everything works.
你在说什么呀
What are you talking about?
这是萨姆森
This is Samson.
它不咬人的 特别温顺
He doesn't bite. He's harmless.
你想抚摸它吗
Do you want to stroke him?
它咬了我
It bit me!
严格地说 蝎子不咬人 它们螫人
Ah, now, technically, scorpions don't bite, they sting.
这是蝎子
Scorpion?!
接下来会发生什么 我会死吗
So what happens now, then, do I die, or what?
实际上 尽管很疼 一般螫你几下没事的
Well, in fact, though painful, stings are harmless,
- 除非你很倒霉 - 我就是很倒霉
- unless you're very unlucky. - I am very unlucky!
你看看我这人生
Look at my life!
莱斯利 别大喊大叫的 我在工作呢
Leslie, please stop shouting, I'm trying to work.
- 我刚刚被蝎子咬了 - 他的意思是被螫
- I've just been bitten by a scorpion! - He means stung.
总而言之...
Anyway, er...
开始喜欢手风琴了吗
Coming round to the accordion?
有一点吧
Erm... A tiny bit.
好 因为我打算在婚礼上献个丑
Good. Cos I'm playing at our wedding.
那只羊应该在这里吗
Is that supposed to be there?
一定是围栏破了
Must be a hole in the fence.
总有一只会溜出来
Always one who escapes.
确实是这样啊
Isn't there just.
没关系 我还有一架
Never mind, I have another one.
我的手风琴就像我的孩子
My accordions are like my children.
不久之后就不需要它们了
So I won't be needing them much longer.
因为你的孩子可以给我带来欢乐
I'll have your children to entertain me.
我... 感觉不太舒服 斯文 我可以现在回家吗
I er... I feel a bit odd, Sven, do you mind if I wander home?
是我说错什么了吗 还是做的饭不好吃
Something I said? Cooked?
不是 我只是... 太累了
No, no, it's er... it's just been a bit stressful,
还有一两天就要举办婚礼了
you know, the wedding in a day or two.
- 我送你回家 - 不用
- I'll walk you home. - No.
不用 呼吸一下新鲜空气就行
No, the... the air will do me good.
今晚过得很愉快
It's been lovely.
我当然害怕啊
Of course I'm panicking!
我的手就像是被煮了一个小时
My hand looks like I've boiled it for an hour.
几乎看不出来
It hardly shows.
但是别让母亲看见 她会很操心的
But don't let Mother see it, she'll be upset.
莱斯利 放松 没什么好担心的
Leslie, relax, you have nothing to worry about,
除非你非常倒霉
unless you are very unlucky.
非常倒霉 你看看我的手 昆虫专家
Very unlucky? Yes, well, take a look at that, Professor Insect.
实际上 严格说
In fact, technically,
蝎子是蛛形纲动物 不是昆虫
scorpions are arachnids, rather than insects.
是的 看起来有过敏性反应
Yes, there seems to be an allergic reaction.
我认为你一早醒来就没事了
I suspect it will be fine in the morning.
蝎子不喜欢被关起来 它们发怒了
Scorpions don't like being caged, they lash out.
我是不是做了错事 西奥
Am I doing a bad thing, Theo,
把蝎子抓起来 把别的动物也抓来
keeping scorpions, keeping anything?
那是因为你想更好地理解研究它们
Well, you want to understand and experience them more.
这也算是保护动物
That's what conservation is.
大家好
Oh, hello.
出什么事了吗
Anything happen here?
斯文怎么样
How was Sven?
他...
He was...
我说不清
I don't know.
- 结果怎么样 - 说实话 不太顺利
- And? - Not a great success, really.
怎么了
Why?
拉里 你是混艺术圈的
Larry, you move in artistic circles.
你觉得斯文可能是同性恋吗
Do you think Sven might be queer?
- 你也这么觉得 - 我发现了一些照片
- You got there, too. - I found the photographs.
大多数人都在某些程度上 对同性有好感
Most humans are attracted to their own gender to some degree.
话是这么说 但是... 他看起来非常有好感
Well yes, but... well, he looked really attracted.
说同性恋不合法其实是诽谤
It's a scandal that homosexuality is outlawed.
他们害怕什么啊 难道我们都抛弃自己的妻子...
What are they scared of? That we'll all ditch our wives, and...
对不起
Sorry.
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
我又该怎么办
And what am I going to do?
干得好 鲁格勒斯雅 太棒了
Ah, well done, Lugaretzia, bravo. Kali douleia.
这是我的工作 亲爱的
Douleia, agapi mou. Douleia.
格里 在婚宴之前 你要处理好动物园的安全问题
Gerry? That zoo needs to be made safe before the reception.
好了 你们这对鸳鸯 还有婚礼要准备呢
Right, you lovebirds, we've got a wedding to prepare,
别慢吞吞的 南希 把你的蜡笔拿走
let's not dawdle! Nancy, put your crayons away!
拉里 帮帮忙 我受不了这样
Larry, please, I can't stand this.
- 这就是家庭生活 - 你之前总是第一个
- This is family life. - And you've always been the first
质疑这一点 为个人自由斗争
to question it, to argue for personal freedom
而不是无脑地效忠 而你现在就像...
over mindless allegiance. And now you're acting like...
他们是我的家人 我爱他们
They're my family and I love them!
我的意思是
By which I mean,
我理解他们 他们难过的时候 我也难过
I understand them and when they suffer, I suffer,
不管他们的问题多么荒谬
however ludicrous their problems.
我真不敢相信自己会这么说
And I... can't believe I'm saying this.
我也有自己的生活 我也不相信自己会这么说
But I have my own life. And I can't believe that I'm saying this,
但是我的生活在英国 而且我想回家
but it's back in England and I want to go home.
请你和我一起走
With you, please.
在这里怎么了 隔壁还有一件小屋
What happened to staying here? There's a shack next door.
不 我们需要离开这里 亲爱的
No, we need to get away, sweetheart,
这样我们能一起探索自己的人生
so we can explore our own life together.
- 谢谢你 西奥 - 谢什么呀
- Thank you, Theo. - What for?
帮我的忙
Helping me.
大家对这里感兴趣 真是让人激动
People were interested. It was so exciting.
我知道
I know.
莱斯利真可怜啊 他太倒霉了 不是吗
It's a shame about Leslie. He really is unlucky, isn't he?
他一直很倒霉 不会有大碍吧
Always. Is he going to be all right?
但愿不会 配崔迪斯医生又不在
I hope so. Dr Petridis is away again.
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
莱斯利的不幸 可能是一个征兆
Leslie's mishap, perhaps it's a sign.
我的意思是 不一定要养着才能爱它们
I mean, we don't need to keep them to love them.
我理解你
I know.
是时候把它们都放生了吗
Is it time to set them all free?
我们可以明天在婚礼上放生
We could do it at the wedding party tomorrow,
作为某种事的... 象征
as a symbol of... something.
好的
All right.
你这一整天都干什么了
What have you been doing all day?
还有十二个小时 你就要成为路易莎夫人了
In 12 hours, you're due to be Mrs Louisa...
斯文姓什么
What is Sven's surname?
伦布拉德
Lundblad.
那你真不该嫁给他
Then you really shouldn't marry him.
我得嫁 鲁格勒斯雅都做好了结婚蛋糕
I have to, Lugaretzia's made a wedding cake.
是啊 我估计她把岛上的李子干都用完了
Yes, I don't think there's a spare prune left on the island.
莱斯利一直在
And Leslie's been running
- 紧锣密鼓地做准备 - 是的
- a tight ship with the preparations. - Yes.
我把他的剪贴板拿走了 然后他又做了个新的
I took his clipboard away and he made another one.
你知道自己该做什么
You know what you have to do.
和斯文谈谈
Talk to Sven.
之前想如果我不说的话 问题也许就会消失
I was hoping if I didn't, the problem would go away.
遇到问题就逃避有用吗
Has being an ostrich been a success for you in the past?
没有 我们还是谈谈你吧
No. Let's talk about you.
尽管我很自恋 喜欢谈论自己的问题
Much as I love me, and talking about me,
我们还是改天再谈吧
let's do that another time.
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
当然
Sure.
我本不该那么做的 但是...
I shouldn't've done it, but erm...
我看了你的照片
I looked through your photos.
你和... 另一个男人照的
Of you... with men.
是这样的 我和其他男人拍过照片
It's true, I've been photo'd with men.
不光是拍照 斯文 你在...
Not just photographed, Sven, you were...
亲吻你的朋友
you were kissing your friend.
你和女性的照片呢
Where are the women?
难道你想让我和很多女人寻欢作乐吗
What, you want me to have had sex with lots of women?
此时此刻我确实是这么想的
Right now, yes, I'd love that.
- 这太荒谬了 - 相信我
- This is absurd. - Believe me,
要不是我们今天就要结婚
I wouldn't care if you were homosexual
我才不在乎你是不是同性恋
if we weren't getting married today.
我的第一段婚姻很美满
I had a lovely first marriage,
但是结婚是很艰难的 斯文
but being married is hard, Sven,
而且婚姻不能建立在一个巨大的谎言之上
and it cannot be based on a big, fat lie.
很明显 我过去是喜欢过男人
Well, clearly I used to like men, that way.
但那已经是很久之前了
But it was a while ago.
你有没有和女人同床过
Have you ever slept with a woman?
有一次差点 但是我想了想还是算了
It was close once but, you know, I think I'll be good.
这不公平 斯文
This isn't fair, Sven.
要是我没有意外地发现你的秘密
If I hadn't chanced upon your secret life,
今晚我就会来到卧室
I would've come to our bedroom tonight expecting,
期待着一段激情
quite frankly, a bit of a show, and...
和一股巨大的释放感 结果呢
and a huge sense of release. And what would've happened?
我会... 我本来会尽力的
Well, I would... I will give it a go.
你为什么想娶我
Why do you want to marry me?
因为我喜欢和你在一起
Because I love being with you.
还想建立一个自己的家庭
And I want a family of my own.
你想也别想
Well, you can't bloody have one.
你知道爱上男人是什么感觉吗
You know what it's like to love men?
就像是在一座真正的监狱里
It's like being in prison, real prison,
充满娇饰和谎言
prison of pretending and... lies.
按照官方说法 我们是患有精神疾病的 你知道吗
We are officially mentally ill, do you know that?
- 我能克服这一点很重要 - 为什么要克服
- It's important I overcome this. - Overcome it?
这是你的一部分
It's part of you.
我必须要
I have to.
我来到这座岛上 以抛弃过去的那一切
I came to this island to put all that in the past.
不
No.
我很抱歉 斯文 但我不能嫁给你
I am so sorry, Sven, but no.
不管我们多么深爱对方
No matter how much we love each other...
这对我们都不公平
it's not right for either of us.
这段婚姻充其量 就是给生活又披了层羊皮
And a marriage would just be more of a lie than your life is now.
也许等我们满头白发 这段婚姻还能成
Maybe if we were both 80, it would work.
我可以等的 如果你也可以
I can wait, if you can.
- 你得去做点香肠 - 一会再说
- You need to cook the little sausages. - Later.
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
我的小说被接受 准备发表了
My novel has been accepted for publication,
因为科孚鼓舞了我当作家
which, because Corfu inspired me as a writer,
这让我在决定去留的时候 更加艰难
makes my decision whether to stay even harder.
你之前从来没问过我建议
You've never asked me for advice before.
这种感觉真好
So nice.
是啊
Yeah.
总之...
Anyway...
你爱你的女朋友 直到她把你甩了...
you loved your girlfriend, until she dumped you...
所以你想想抛弃她的痛苦
so imagine the pain of abandoning her.
听着 你特别讨厌
Look. You're incredibly annoying.
你都能做英国的讨厌代言人了
Y-you could represent England for annoying.
但是你不要走
But don't leave.
女朋友分分合合 但家人是一辈子的
Girlfriends come and go, but families are for ever.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们需要谈谈
I think we need to talk.
- 什么 我们三个人吗 - 不 就我和他 莱斯利
- What, the three of us? - No, not the three of us, Leslie.
哦 抱歉
Oh, yes, sorry.
你为什么偏偏挑今天催我
Why are you rushing me? Today of all days.
这项婚礼又不会改变什么
The wedding doesn't change anything.
跟婚礼没关系
Not the stupid wedding,
今天是我听说小说被发表的一天
the day I hear my novel's being published.
你知道我很为你开心 拉里
You know how pleased I am for you, Larry.
但是我关心我们的未来
But I need to know our future.
我的家人也没有那么糟
My family aren't that bad, are they?
我的母亲爱你
My mother loves you.
那她为什么要告诉我 你对我就没忠心过
So why did she tell me you'd never be faithful to me, then?
什么
What?
拉里 不要去 这跟她没关系
Larry, don't. It's not about her.
拉里你来了 很好
Larry, good.
婚礼我们不办了
There isn't going to be a wedding.
为什么
Why?
我们意识到... 互相很喜欢彼此
We realised... we're very fond of each other,
但是不合适
but not in the right way.
所以不是因为他喜欢男人
So not because he prefers men?
是那个原因 但是给客人就这么说
Well, yes, that. But just tell the guests, as I say,
我们意识到...
we realise we're very...
互相很喜欢彼此 但是不合适
Fond of each other but not in the right way.
斯文来决定怎么给大家一个交代
It's up to Sven to decide what to tell people.
所以不办婚礼了... 但是要办最好的派对
So no wedding... but the best party ever.
好了各位 我们还有一...
OK, people, so we've got one... Argh!
一个小时到婚礼... 啊不 是欢乐派对
One... one hour until the wedding... well, th-the knees-up.
所以... 嗯
So, basically... yeah.
你是不是告诉南希 我是个拈花惹草的混球
Did you tell Nancy I'm a philandering bastard?
- 对不起 - 根本不是真的
- I'm so sorry. - It's not even true.
我或许天天谈论性 想着性
I may talk about sex all the time, and think about it
还很精彩地描写出来 但是我没有去做
and write about it, brilliantly, but I don't do it.
我坚定不移地等着南希 整整五个月
I've waited steadfastly for Nancy for five months!
我那时不想让你离开
I didn't want you to leave.
觉得该轮到我自私点了
It was my turn to be selfish.
"拉里 我要坐五点的轮船回家
'Larry, catching the five o'clock ferry home.
我真心地希望你能和我一起 爱你的南希留"
I hope with all my heart you will join me. Love, Nancy.'
马戈 你忘了穿裙子了
Margo, you forgot to put your skirt on.
天哪
Oh, God!
你如愿了 斯皮罗斯
Well, you erm... you got your wish, Spiros.
我不嫁给斯文了
I'm not marrying Sven.
啊 路易莎
Oh, Louisa.
你可以告诉大家吗
Er... will you tell everyone?
没问题
Of course.
他们很喜欢彼此 但是...
They are really fond of each other, just erm...
但是不合适
just not in the right way.
没事 我们一起给你找个新的希腊丈夫
OK, together we'll find you a new, Greek husband.
- 太快了吗 - 是的
- Too soon? - Yeah.
不要担心 我检查过了莱斯利的手臂 治疗了一下
Don't worry, I've examined Leslie's arm and treated it.
应该是没有问题了
I'm pretty sure we can save it.
什么 他的手臂
What? His arm?
早上不会感到僵硬了
Save it from feeling a bit stiff in the morning.
- 好吧 - 干杯
- Right. - Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
别光站在那里 和蜡像似的
Don't just stand there, misting over,
快过来祝贺
come and congratulate the
伯爵夫人离开了她那该死的房子
Countess on getting out of the bloody house.
- 你感觉怎么样 - 有点像在走钢丝
- How are you feeling? - A little like a tightrope walker
试着不往下面看
trying not to look down.
- 喝杯酒吧 - 不 很明显那会让她感觉更糟
- Have a drink. - No, that makes it worse, apparently.
哦 那就别喝酒
Oh, don't have a drink.
我们看来是错过了仪式
Er... apparently we've missed the ceremony,
但是... 你母亲嫁给了谁
but... who did your mother marry?
大家伙好啊
Hello, party!
- 马克斯来了 - 还有... 唐纳德
- Max has arrived! - And... and Donald.
但主要是马克斯
But mainly Max.
失陪
Excuse me.
- 你好啊 马吉 - 你好
- Hello, Margy. - Hello.
你确实很会办派对啊
You know how to throw a party.
这个嘛...
Well...
在科孚呆六个月 就像在伯恩茅斯呆了一辈子
Six months in Corfu, feels like a lifetime in Bournemouth.
我不知道究竟是这里的气氛 还是这杯酒
I don't know if it's the atmosphere, or the wine,
但我开始喜欢听手风琴了
but I'm actually starting to enjoy the accordion.
我得告诉拉里 他总是...
I'll have to tell Larry, he's always...
我知道格里和我志趣相投
I knew Gerry was a kindred spirit
当时我们一起观察了
when together, we watched
蜣螂一家三个小时
a family of dung beetles for three hours.
格里很爱动物 但是...
So Gerry loves animals, but...
一只巨大的蝎子 蛰了我这里
A scorpion, massive, and it stung me there.
那种疼痛一般人都受不了 所以...
The pain would have actually killed most men, so...
不好意思 你们继续
Sorry, sorry. Carry on.
谢谢你 格里很爱动物
Thank you. Gerry loves animals,
但是爱的一部分是学会放手
but part of loving is knowing when to let go.
所以今天我们要把我珍爱的动物家族
So today we are releasing my precious animal family
放生
back into the wild,
但愿它们可以和我们一样 茁壮成长 欢乐每一天
where, hopefully, like us, they'll thrive and have fun
如果幸运的话 可以繁衍生息
and if they're lucky, multiply.
所以...
So...
住手
Stop.
我还需要和它们多呆一段时间
I need to be with them a little longer.
远远地观察它们不够
It's not enough to observe them from a distance.
要想把它们研究透 就要每天和它们在一起
To understand them properly, you need to be with them every day
抱着它们 闻着它们
and hold them and smell them.
总之... 对不起
Anyway... sorry.
也许下周再说吧
Maybe next week.
请回去接着享受派对吧
Please, go back and enjoy the party.
谢天谢地 我还以为你真的会
Thank goodness. I thought for a horrible moment
把它们全都放生了呢
you were going to go ahead with it.
干得好
Well done.
这很新鲜
This feels new.
谢谢你 拉里
Thank you, Larry.
马戈告诉了我你的那本书
Margo told me about your book.
我为你感到自豪
I'm very proud of you.
这是你应该的
So you should be.
我为你们所有人感到自豪
I'm proud of all of you.
- 那么 接下来怎么办 - 你吗
- So, what's next? - For you?
有句话说得好 当你从马背上摔下来时...
Well, you know what they say, when you fall off a horse...
- 就不再去骑马了吗 - 赶紧再爬上去
- Give up horse-riding? - Get back on again quickly.
斯皮罗斯说了类似的话
You know, Spiros said something similar.
虽然没那么委婉
Only not as nicely.
在这座岛上 总有适合你的人
Somewhere on this island, there's someone for you.
我总是幻想有一天 你们四个人都能找到...
You know, I just dream of the day when all four of you find...
幸福 美满 以及爱情
happiness and fulfilment and love.
这或许没戏了
This may not happen.
但让它实现 是我的职责
It's my job to make it happen.
拭目以待吧
We'll see.